prestigeportraits.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy - Lifetouch Inc.

## US Privacy Policy

Last Updated: July 2018

On April 2, 2018, Lifetouch Inc. joined the Shutterfly family of brands. The following Terms of Service were updated to align the combined companies’ policies and practices where applicable.

Canadian Customers [Click Here](https://lifetouch.ca/privacy)

Lifetouch Inc., located at 11000 Viking Drive in Eden Prairie, Minnesota, 55344 and its corporate affiliates including its parent company Shutterfly Inc. (collectively, “Lifetouch,” “we,” “our,” or “us“) are your trusted providers of photographic products and services to communities, schools, churches, day care centers and families throughout the United States and Canada. At Lifetouch, we are sensitive to the privacy concerns of the individuals we photograph and of visitors to our websites, and we want you to know that your privacy is important to us.

**What does this Policy cover?**

Unless we notify you otherwise in connection with a particular activity, this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) explains how we collect and use information through lifetouch.com and our other general audience websites, applications and services that link to this Policy (each, a “Lifetouch Site”), and the choices you can make about the collection and use of your information. This Policy also addresses information we collect from you when you schedule an appointment to be photographed, order photographs or other products from us, visit or are photographed at one of our offices, studios or on-site photography locations, contact one of our customer service representatives, or respond to a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes that we administer. This Policy also explains how we use certain basic personal information we may collect in advance of “Picture Day” from the organization you (or your child) are affiliated with (for example, your child’s school, your university, your employer or your place of worship, each an “Organization”) when we are engaged by that Organization to photograph you or your child (see Picture Day Information below).

A separate privacy policy, not this Policy, applies to websites, applications and online services that are designed for the use and benefit of the schools and school districts Lifetouch provides service to for their administrative and educational purposes and which are used by or at the direction of teachers or other school or district employees (a “School Service”). For the privacy policy for our School Services, please refer to the policy linked to from those sites or contact us using the information posted at the end of this Policy or through your Lifetouch school account representative.

**What information do you collect from and about me?**

_Information You Provide to Us._ We collect personal information (information that identifies you as an individual) and other information from you through your use of this Lifetouch Site, such as when you register for an account, schedule a photography appointment or place an order; when you visit or contact one of our studios, offices or customer service representatives; or when you respond to a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes that we administer. This information may include some or all of the following:

  * your name
  * the names of and your relationship to family members or others Lifetouch is photographing as part of your photography session or whose photographs you wish to order
  * your physical address
  * your child’s birthdate
  * your email address
  * your telephone number(s)
  * credit card and other payment information
  * information about the Organization you are affiliated with, if relevant to your photography session (for example, if you are ordering school pictures, we may ask you to identify your child’s school)
  * your photos and other content that you upload to the Lifetouch Site, if applicable (“Your Content”)

_Information from Other Sources._ We may obtain personal information about you from other sources. For example, in preparation for Picture Day at an Organization (for example, a church, university, sports league or business) that engages Lifetouch as its photographer, Lifetouch requires certain basic roster information from that Organization about its photo subjects in advance (the “Organizational Data”). We collect Organizational Data only as needed for Picture Day and related purposes authorized by the Organization. For example, we collect photo subject names so that we can match names and images for each photography session and for efficient distribution to our customers. We also may receive your email or other contact information from the Organization you are affiliated with in order to deliver Picture Day-related communications on its behalf, or for inclusion in the Organization’s directory or other publication the Organization has engaged Lifetouch to produce.

Lifetouch does not sell, trade or share Organizational Data with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes, nor do we use such data in ways that are unrelated to the purposes authorized by the Organization. Further information for parents regarding how Lifetouch National School Studios Inc. uses limited school data to conduct Picture Day at schools is available here.

We may also obtain data that is publicly available or from third party sources to improve the accuracy of and add to what we know about our customers, for the purposes described in this policy.

_Information You Provide About Others._ If you choose to share your photographs or other information with someone else through a Lifetouch Site feature, we will use the personal information you provide (for example the e-mail address of the recipient) to fulfill your request and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Please be aware that your name and/or email address could be provided to us by another user of the Lifetouch Site for the same purpose.

_Information from Social Networking and Third Party Services._ A Lifetouch Site may allow you to interact with or through social networking services such as Facebook and Twitter (“Social Features”). Examples of Social Features include enabling you to “like” or “share” content or to log into a Lifetouch Site using your username and password for the third party social network. If you choose to connect your Lifetouch account with a third party social network, the social network may share information about you with us such as your public profile, e-mail address and friend list. If you choose to “like” or share content, information about you may be publicly displayed on the social network. You should review the privacy policy of that third party social network and check your privacy settings through that social network. If you post information on a social networking or other third party service that references Lifetouch or its products or services (e.g., via a Twitter hashtag), we may publish your post on a Lifetouch Site.

_Other information about you._ In addition to the personal information we collect as described above, the Lifetouch Site uses cookies and similar technologies that collect certain non-personal technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites, such as what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter the Lifetouch Site, and the pages and content you view and / or select as you tour our site. This technology, including cookies placed by our third-party service providers, helps us customize your current and future visits to the site (for example, by storing the contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out), and it allows us to compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our site. We and our service providers use these statistics in connection with Lifetouch marketing programs and to improve our website design and content. Our third party service providers may also use such technology to provide you with Lifetouch advertisements on other websites and online services, and may combine this technical information with other information they gather about your visits to other websites and online services to show you advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you (“Interest-Based Advertising”).

If you do not want the site to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies from the site or to alert you before a cookie is placed on your computer. Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s “Help” menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Please note that cookie-based opt-outs only apply to the specific computer and browser on which the opt-out cookie is applied. If you accept a cookie, you can delete it at any time through your web browser. However, if you choose not to accept cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of some of this website’s features. Also, the Network Advertising Initiative and the Digital Advertising Alliance offer opt-out tools to assist you in managing your choices for participating companies that use cookies for Interest-Based Advertising and cross-app advertising. For more information about these tools please visit: NAI Opt-Out Page (web browser only) and DAA Opt-Out Page (web browser only). You can also install Google Analytics’ opt-out browser add-on by visiting https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

**California’s “Do Not Track” Notice:** “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) is a preference you can set in your web browser to let the sites you visit know that you do not want them collecting information about you. Our sites do not currently respond to “Do Not Track” settings. For further details regarding DNT, visit [donottrack.us](http://donottrack.us/).

**How does Lifetouch use the personal information it collects about me?**

We responsibly limit the use and disclosure of your personal information. We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to provide the products or services or benefits you request, or information about them,
  * to produce and deliver photographic products and services per our agreement with the Organization you are affiliated with, as applicable,
  * to develop and improve our products and services,
  * to improve the content of our site and the services we provide, and their usefulness to you,
  * to deliver Lifetouch marketing communications and promotional materials that may be of interest to you, and
  * to protect the security or integrity of our databases or website, to take precautions against liability, and to detect and remediate violations of our Terms & Condition or other misuse of the Lifetouch Site.

In addition, your personal information may be incorporated into products that we are providing to you and your associated Organization. For example, if Lifetouch is producing student ID cards, we need the student ID number to execute picture day and deliver services to the school ; a church directory we are printing may include contact information along with church members’ names and photos per your church’s specifications. You should notify your Organization if you wish to exclude your photo or other personal information from such products and services.

If you upload Your Content to a Lifetouch Site, it remains your property. Lifetouch will only use Your Content to fulfill your orders and otherwise as directed by you.

Please be assured that Lifetouch does not use its customers’ photographs in marketing or advertising materials to third parties without first obtaining a photo release from the photo subject (or, in the case of a minor, the photo subject’s parent or legal representative).

Lifetouch does not sell, trade or share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes. We do share your personal information within Lifetouch and with your affiliated Organization (if applicable) for the purposes described in this Policy. We may also share this information with third parties who provide support services to us such as helping us deliver communications, fulfill customer orders, enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, process credit card orders and the like. If so, these parties are authorized to use the personal information solely in conjunction with the specific service they provide to or on behalf of Lifetouch.

We may also be required to share or transfer your personal information in other, limited circumstances, for example, to respond to judicial process, to comply with state, federal or local laws, to protect the security or integrity of our databases or website, to take precautions against liability, in the event of a corporate reorganization or, to the extent required by law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies. Your information may be transferred to successor organization if, for example, we transfer the ownership or operation of this Site to another organization if we merge with or are acquired by another organization, or if we liquidate our assets. Your information may also be shared with or transferred to companies that become our affiliates in the future through a merger or acquisition or liquidation of assets. If such a transfer occurs, the new company’s use of your information will still be subject to this Policy and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us.

**How long do you keep my photos?**

Our goal is to make the photos Lifetouch creates available to our customers for years to come. In partnership with our parent company Shutterfly Inc., Lifetouch offers photo archiving for its customers in many of its photography programs at no additional cost. When you purchase photos from Lifetouch, we may securely retain a digital copy of one or more of your source photos for you to claim and archive in your Shutterfly account, if you wish to do so. If you do not want us to retain your photos for you to claim on your Shutterfly account, you can take steps to have your photos deleted from our systems, subject to certain limitations. Please see our [Terms of Service](https://lifetouch.com/terms-conditions) (“Your Options”) for further details.

Please note that Shutterfly archiving services are available only to customers who purchase Lifetouch photos, whether captured within schools, churches, organizations, portrait studios or other professional photography outlets we operate. Unless purchased by a parent (or by someone with whom the parent has shared the photo), we retain school photos only as long as necessary to satisfy our obligations to the schools we serve.

**What is the SmileSafe® child safety program? Do you share photos with law enforcement?**

Lifetouch does not share its photographs with law enforcement unless a parent or guardian has expressly requested us do so in accordance with our SmileSafe child safety program or on an exceptional basis pursuant to legal process. Lifetouch provides two complimentary SmileSafe photo ID cards annually to the families of each PreK-12 student photographed in participating schools, at no extra cost and regardless of whether the family has purchased photographs. We work in collaboration with the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC), the United States’ leading experts in child protection. If a child is missing, the parent or guardian of that child can request through NCMEC that a Lifetouch photograph of their child be provided to aid search efforts. Lifetouch will respond on a 24/7 basis to aid search efforts. This private, secured system requires parent permission and law enforcement verification, or the receipt of legal process, prior to image release by Lifetouch. Once released, the images can help authorities start an accurate, on-site search. Parents or guardians have complete control over whether or not to initiate sharing a child’s SmileSafe image with law enforcement. As of the date this Policy was last updated, Lifetouch has assisted with more than 2,000 searches and has contributed to the successful recovery of 56 children from 24 states as a direct result of the SmileSafe child safety program.

**What choices do I have about your use of my personal information?**

The goal of our marketing and promotional efforts is to inform you about our products and services, including special promotions and coupons, that may be of interest to you. We may use your contact information to inform you of offers. However, if you are contacted and do not wish to receive further marketing communications, use the means by which you were contacted to let us know. If contacted by postal mail, return the mail to the sender. If contacted by e-mail, reply to the e-mail sender or use the unsubscribe mechanism within the email. If telephoned, notify the person telephoning you that you do not wish to receive further calls from them.

We will act promptly to honor your request and remove your name from the sender’s marketing list. However, even if we remove your name from use in marketing programs, you may still receive communications from the sender for non-marketing purposes, for example in connection with a pending order or customer service issue, or from other sources who obtained your contact information before we received your request.

**How can I review and update the personal information you have about me?**

If you would like to review, correct or delete your personal information, or if you are the parent or legal guardian of a minor and would like to review, correct or delete that minor’s personal information, you may be able to do so by logging into your account with the Lifetouch Site. If not, please contact us (see For further information below). There may be times when we are unable to fulfill your request – for example, if providing access to your personal information would reveal confidential commercial or proprietary information or personal information about someone else (and we cannot separate your data), if we are prohibited by law from disclosing the information or if we have a legal obligation to retain certain data. We may require additional personal information from you for the purposes of verifying your identity and rights.

**How does Lifetouch safeguard personal information?**

Lifetouch has implemented safeguards reasonably designed to protect against unauthorized access and disclosures of personal information under its control, including appropriate technical, physical and administrative safeguards and security measures. A comprehensive set of IT policies based on ISO 27001/2 governs information systems practices and procedures throughout the Lifetouch enterprise. As a Level 2 merchant transacting over one million credit card transactions per year, Lifetouch is subject to annual third party certification of its compliance with the stringent Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. Please be advised, however, that despite these measures, no website, application, database or system is completely secure or “hacker proof”; accordingly, we cannot guarantee that our information security safeguards will never be compromised.

**Other Information about this Policy**
